Hi! I'm John. I'm a developer on Wordbots.
Today I'm going to show you how to use Wordbots's powerful card creator tools.
To get an idea of how we represent cards in
the cart creator, we can hit the Randomize
button to generate a new random card
with all the details filled in.
Notice we are only generating robots.
To generate other types of cards, we can modify the card type drop-down.
Let's go back to generating robots.
If you get stuck and can't think of the
word you want, we've included a
dictionary, thesaurus, and a list of
keywords to help you make the card of
your dreams.
Let's look at the tools the thesaurus
gives us. Here we can see examples of
sentences that generate the "destroy"
action on a card.
Let's try it out.
Hmm, the parser didn't understand that,
but it gave us some suggestions.
Looks like "destroyed" can't be used as a
passive ability on a robot. One thing we
could do is change this card to an Event
type. Let's accept the recommended fix instead.
If we hover over this word on the card
we can see what effect the "Startup"
keyword has. We can also check the
keyword reference. We can see "Startup"
means "when our card is played". Let's make
this card a little less powerful.
We'll only make this destroy adjacent
structures. To get an idea of how we can
do this, check the dictionary.
There are also other action life cycles
that we can use with this card. Let's
make it trigger every time we move.
If you're feeling curious, you can take a
look at what this card looks like to the
card parser. Here we see an internal
representation of what the parser sees
when it reads your card.
Let's go ahead and give this card a name
How about Structure Smasher?
To complete our card, we need to assign
stats like attack, health, speed, and
finally, a card cost. Time to test out our card!
In this mode, we can alter the decks of
both players with any card in our
collection. We'll use this to give both
players a lot of structures our Smasher
can smash.
We have to play a couple of structures
on the board to get a good feel for our
card's ability.
Now let's play our Structure Smasher and
try moving it around.
Would you look at that? When we move our
robot around, the adjacent structures are
getting destroyed. Unfortunately it looks
like a destroys our structures – that's
no good. Hit the Forfeit button to leave
test mode. Let's try to make it a little
better. Let's see if we can make it only
destroy enemy structures. First let's
check the dictionary to see how the word
"enemy" is used.
Looks like this card is ready to use.
Let's add it to our collection.
Now you can use this card to make your
own decks in the deck creator.